dude have you played around with cursor
I've been using cursor to write an app
dude it is unreal is it not it's pretty
interesting um
so I dude why do you guys say it like
that right as I take a sip of my coffee
[Music]
[Applause]
hey guys our sponsor project Discovery
has dropped a new tool in collaboration
with Google's own mandian team called
TLD finder okay picture the SubFinder
but for top level domains need I say
anymore check it
out listen I'm getting roasted dude
you're just rolling up to Twitter like
all right guys I'm freaking expensing
these deine impact pies dude what a
tweet man what a tweet
listen listen um it's in policy okay I
get I get a perdum for dinner I chose
TOS spend it at McDonald's okay I open
the McDonald's app and there's genin
impact apple pie sour how do you say no
to that how do you say I was like I was
like I like ordered them and I was like
damn I just realized I'm GNA have to
file an itemized expense report for the
gench and impact apple pies oh my gosh
dud that's amazing I'm um I'm looking at
this little like side picture here in
Riverside where like it shows your your
just the I think the thumbnail the first
frame that happens when you loaded up
your camera dude it looks like you just
rolled out of bed in your
hair okay all right guys sorry about all
that okay um Joel where you at man I'm
in
La yeah I'm in La for a couple days I'm
I'm here for a conference so nice I'm uh
I'm just popping in and out but uh yeah
we're back on that East Coast West Coast
time difference yeah yeah it's I mean it
works out well to be honest because
you're an early bird so um yeah yeah
yeah it's not too bad but it was a
little bit difficult getting myself out
of bed this morning I will say I'll say
it works it works out well for
me you're like ah 88 a.m I'm like ah 5
a.m. 5 amm oh my gosh that's great dude
well um yeah just to just to give Jolan
out here there was a little bit of
miscommunication this week and Joel did
not know that he was going to be on the
Pod this week so umel like you ready to
record tomorrow and I was like
uh y so thanks for showing up dude
thanks for for doing the homework and uh
you got the got the air rocking the
airpods today so um if this is your
first episode whoever is listening I'm
sorry this is not our normal audio
quality but um you know we show up thing
I will say one thing I will say there
was a rumor there was a rumor I don't
know if this is true or like when it's
going to happen but apparently Apple's
going to be rolling out a change at some
point where the airpods are no longer
going to switch into handset mode when
you're using the microphone and they'll
stay on like the 48 khz or whatever and
I think it's GNA happen like over over
thread or something what does that mean
so when you're so normally like your
headphones like you know how like
there's an audio quality difference when
you hop onto a onto a call yeah it's
it's because it's using both the
microphone and it's using both input and
output so it runs at a lower bit rate
and and so that's like why it sound like
[__] where if you set the like if I set
it to only use the audio and to use the
microphone from my laptop it'll switch
back to sounding good so Apple's
apparently making a change where they're
gonna make it so the airpods can do both
without needing to switch quality um I
don't know we'll see we'll see we'll see
man I I saw tweet about that a couple
weeks ago I I I said yes but I've never
used airpods in my life so I have no
idea what you were talking about yeah I
I've heard prent yeah I'm I'm a pretty
big fan um I actually just bought well I
have mixed experiences my Maxes I just
had them break and thankfully they were
under Apple Care and they fixed them
very quickly but during that process I
then had to buy a new pair of prows the
little tiny ones um and I've had a pair
of of Pros for a while and I'm quite
happy with them because I like thrown
them in my pocket it it's just like I
lose headphones so fast too I don't know
what it is like I'm not a particularly
irresponsible person when it comes to
like keeping thing like I never lose my
wallet my phone my keys but for some
reason headphones are just not important
to me like and I just and so I mean I
just always get these like same $40 pair
you know because it's you get a good
enough quality where it's like okay this
is good quality but if I lose it it's
not like oh this hurts you know that's
interesting that's interesting know I I
love them cuz I just throw them in my
pocket and I have them with me like
everywhere I go so yeah well I dig shout
out to Ben for all the airpods that he's
lost we uh we know that that's a legacy
of his but all right so I meant to start
out this episode a little bit
differently Joel but I I I'll do a
little story time dude I saw I saw this
story and I I got some questions but I'm
Gonna Let You Go ahead dude this is this
is just the hacker mentality okay I
think this is the I just wanted to do I
just wanted to share this story so that
we can talk about the struggle that
hackers feel internally ethical hackers
right because I'm I'm driving down
actually I'm not driving I'm sitting in
the passenger seat I almost always drive
our our car when Mariah and I are
together right but for some reason this
time Mariah's driving and this [__]
cuts her off completely and like she has
to slam on the brakes and she and I'm
looking at this person I was like I can
see this license plate very clearly
right I'm like man wouldn't it be cool
if I like like if I could just pick a
couple black hat things to do how sick
would it be to just be able to hand out
like Road retribution for all of these
like terrible sins that people commit
while driving right so I could just say
like that guy is GNA get like like a ton
of toll fins or something like that
right and just like you need to work for
the Department of Transportation I never
do it I never do it I'm I'm purely on
the white hat side but how cool would
that be to just be able to be like I got
your license plate number you're done
for buddy you're done
Ford you're done Bud all right you're
not that guy pal um you I know I'm not
going to shout out any hackers in
particular but I know a couple hackers
that have like some automation framework
surrounding license plate numbers and
stuff like that um yeah I know the same
one you're talking about I'm glad you
you phrase it that way because I was
gonna call them out by name yeah yeah
but but uh you know it would be cool if
there was some way to you know if it
wasn't just read if it was right you
know if we could if we could just be
like you you deserve fine you're gonna
get
fined so uh maybe it's time to do an
ethical hacking Endeavor on the
DMV I don't know man well it it's it's
not and and the thing is man I'm not a
particularly Road ragy person so I I
figured I'd share this on the Pod
because it surprised me a little bit I'm
like why why do I want to do that you
know like and I think it's because they
cut off Mariah you know every once in a
while it happens to me I get I get a
little I get a I get a road rage and in
well incident maybe that's not the right
way to phrase it I'm not like getting
out of my car and yelling at someone um
usually it's the other way around oh my
gosh but it's not because I caused
anything it's because like I'll flip
them off and then they'll flip me back
off and then it just escalates dude
whenever anybody flips me off I just I
do I do this I do the little I do a
little heart side I do the heart back
that's crazy bro that that just gets
them that gets him if you flip them off
like they're like oh well screw that guy
you know he flipped me off I flipped him
off but if you give him the heart and if
you hit him with the little Korean drama
heart then they're like like what is
this what is wrong with you know it gets
in their head a little bit more right
you know am I wrong I'm not wrong uh
yeah man that's super intimidating
you're right uh I feel threatened yeah
you're you're welcome for that um all
right dude yeah well we'll we'll leave
that we'll leave that at that um but so
let's let's let's hit some of these
topics we got we got a pretty lean
episode today guys I'm uh I'm just
coming off a live hacking event the um
the show and tells were just like an
hour ago so I am feeling a little bit
high from those because it's always
amazing to see what the other hackers um
come up with and I will also give a
shout out to uh to cosmin inhibitor 181
because him and I both there in this
live hacking event that were working on
there's a massive scope massive and him
and I both happen to coincidentally
choose the same little minimal a
application that was just a small part
of a small part of the scope right and
just went Ham on that for the whole live
hacking it and um we both found 15 plus
bugs um cosman's substantially more
critical than mine but we didn't dup at
all is that amazing I was gonna ask wow
that's crazy yeah and and it's just it
blows the mind a little bit because like
cosmin cosmin and I you know we we've
had vul overlap before but it just CU I
I I remember getting to the end of this
event just a couple days ago and just
being like
wow I think I found everything that
could be possibly found on this app you
know like I I know everything about this
app like ain't nobody can teach me
nothing about this app and then cosin
comes in there with like six crits you
know yeah then the professor walks in
seriously and I'm like and he just found
some way to get around a core protection
and it just unlocked a bunch of new
scope um nice so that's cool yeah it
just goes to show Even if you you know I
preach a lot on the pot about going deep
and becoming the world expert on an
application right and and you know I'm
going to say I thought I did it you know
at this event but there's always more to
learn about it man there's always more
to learn about D I've been parcking on a
couple different random like public
programs yeah and uh and we've been
duping like crazy it's on like the on
like stuff that like we shouldn't be
duping on either and it's like we're
duping by like two days and it's like
super annoying
um and like I've never had this many
dupes before like I never dup at life
hacking events ever and like uh this
time around I am are you duping with
your pair like with the person you're
working on it with or yeah we're we're
collabing so we're we're duping on like
random people you're duping on somebody
else yeah somebody else dud that's super
annoying and it's close too it's not
like something that the like like there
was one there was one I was talking
about this in the Discord that like uh
originally it was duped by like 2 years
and I was like okay that's super
annoying like that this was open for 2
years and then like they reopened and
we're like oh actually now we're this
isn't a dupe and then like a couple days
later they duped it again on a different
bug that was two days before ours oh my
gosh I was like dang can't win here so
so demotivating I don't understand you
know like I understand that they have to
do that right I understand that it's a
part of their job to go in and be like
ah actually this is a dupe but like if
you do something like that where you
open up and you undo it and then you red
it again a couple days later like you
got to understand if you have any
empathy you got to understand what that
does to the hacker yeah right I mean
it's terribly demotivating yeah yeah so
I don't know man I I did get a little
bit of a shot in the gut though when I
when I thought I had really like uh
wrecked this application and then Cosman
comes in there with like six crits like
the bypass that he found was something
you would have found no I mean it was I
mean so I think I would have found it
eventually but the thing is I
specifically decided to ignore um a
certain part of the application because
I thought that the impact was not going
to be uh I'll just be a little bit more
clear about it um I I decided to
ignore because I'm like you know what
the impact here is a little bit low I
kind of want to go for the for the Juicy
Juice right yeah
um yeah and and um and so I I ignored
that part and
I there was an additional piece of
impact that could be achieved by using a
different component um with within that
environment so I I might have to bleep
some of that we'll see we'll see sorry
sorry if I do guys but um yeah it was it
was a very it was a very creative
approach and I think you know at the end
of the day he just knew more about that
part of the application than I did and
that's because I didn't go as deep as I
could have and that's the thing that I
love about these live hacking events man
is you always get to see how the other
hackers minds work and you get to
fine-tune your own hacker intuition and
your own you know brain radar there um
and and then next time you know next
time I'm going to be a little bit more
thorough about this for sure nice hell
yeah dude that's awesome yo y'all
exciting announcement real quick we are
finally launching the ctbb podcast swag
store yeah that's right the shirts that
Joel and I have been wearing on the Pod
for the past couple months will finally
be available for y'all to purchase at
ctbb Dosh show/ swag we gave out quite a
few of them at Defcon but if you didn't
get your hands on one or maybe you want
some more then definitely check out the
swag store also if you're a critical
thinker on Discord then uh check the
Discord Channel because you'll have a
discount code available for you there or
maybe this is a good opportunity for you
to sign up and become a critical thinker
if you're not already because you'll get
a great discount on the swag um if you
do so all right cool I think that's a
wrap uh anything else I need to tell you
about that I don't think so all right
cool back to the Pod let's go all right
so um we got a couple things we got a
couple writeups we got a couple gadgets
uh we got some cool research that I that
I stumbled upon but first I wanted to go
ahead and handle a uh a community
request here from nbk 2000 on Twitter
saying tell us about some of the stuff
you're doing with cursor uh after I
tweeted about cursor dude have you
played around with cursor I've been
using cursor to write an app dude it is
unreal is it not it's pretty interesting
um
so I dude why do you guys to say it like
that right as I take a sip of my
coffee yeah so I've I've I've been I
used it quite a bit uh over the last
couple weeks um the thing is it can be
really good for certain things um I
think a lot of the hype around it was
very
misleading um wow okay we're gonna have
different takes on this go go go for it
you're an actual Dev so maybe and and
and and for what it's worth for what
it's worth I've been using it to write a
complicated IOS app for the last couple
weeks um so it's not like I'm like I'm
not experienced with it um I've I've
gone back and forth with it quite a bit
and I'm now at the point where I'm like
fully not using it uh I actually
uninstalled it the other day because I'm
now like I'm just just on manual
development and I'll explain it a little
bit why but um cursor so so early on
when I when I first saw it like a lot of
the hype being drummed up they were like
check this thing out there's cursor
composer you just give it this MD file
like you you know describe like how you
want your backend app to work and
whatever and then uh you just feed it
into this and it'll go and create it and
I was like wow that's pretty cool um so
I went and I was testing with it and I
was like oh you know you can you can
actually do this but I was having
trouble like replicating those results
to to the same extent until I started
taking a closer look at those demo
videos and when you look at the demo
videos um the markdown file that they
provided to to cursor in the demo was
create a file called server. TS with the
following content and it's literally
just a code block and like they rewrote
the code for it that's not like so that
doesn't make any sense at all so so that
aside right like taking that with a
grain of salt like the fact that it can
actually get close pretty cool um like
it's very interesting
technology um you know I think like the
context stuff is probably where the
biggest hurdle is like there's just so
much context where you get to a point
and this is why I've switched to manual
development where there's too much
context for a GPT um especially a free
one to be able to do anything meaningful
with and you'll get to a point where it
starts to clobber itself where it'll you
know change things or doesn't have
enough context to to keep things the way
they are or to keep functionality the
same and like as a human like you know
like I don't want to change this I just
want to add this one thing but it will
like change other parts of the
application just to do this one thing or
it'll you know read a class that already
exists even though it should know that
it exists um just for like you know to
get rid of an error message yeah um so
so it'll do like a lot of that kind of
stuff which is a little bit tricky um
but um you know as a whole it's a very
very cool piece of software yeah and so
so I think you're coming I think our
difference in perspective here is is
coming from the fact that you're using
it to actually Cod a large application
right the the project you're working on
is a lot more advanced than anything I'm
working on right and it's also in in a
language I think that that probably I I
I theorize the the AI has less
experience with um for me I'm writing
mostly HTML CSS JavaScript python right
those are those are the ones that I'm
using it for and yeah and I'm most of
the time what I'm coding are proof of
concept exploits right so I'll
essentially say to it like and and I'll
have like cool ideas for this is this is
the cool part right because for for a
hacker like I I often have these cool
ideas for my proof of concept bugs
especially my web stuff that kind of um
utilizes common flows of the web and
like uh you know a user's tendency to be
able to or to wait on a page you know
for a certain amount of time right
without realizing anything's happening
so I can say like hey generate a a
loading bar that takes you know 20
seconds for it to load and and if I had
to code that myself I'd be like I'm not
going to do that but because I can just
tell cursor hey generate that and it
does it it makes my proof of Concepts
much more beautiful and much more
realistic to the program where they can
come to this page and be like oh yeah I
didn't even realize I was sitting on
this page for 20 seconds um and
something's happening in the
background yeah yeah exactly so so
before I was actually having it write an
IOS app um a lot of the experimentation
I was doing with it was around like web
app and stuff and just having like I
won't go into the rabbit hole it's a
it's a very dumb rabbit hole but we were
trying to have it right a very silly web
app I I can't even go into the details
because it's it's too much but um the
point is uh it can do a lot of really
impressive stuff I think one of the more
impressive things is how it can
integrate with libraries so you'll be
like you know I want I want to do this
thing and instead of like expecting that
it's going to home roll like image
recognition or something it'll just pull
some JavaScript library that actually
does it really well and it'll just
implement it and it just works um so you
know there were definitely like for for
more basic web apps it's really good at
that kind of stuff and like you know a
couple files like you said like you know
maybe you need a backend server that
does some specific flow and you just
want like a a little front end like an
HTML thing that you know and could you
do it yourself sure but can you do it in
10 seconds no so exactly curs is kind of
nice for that here's here's the thing
that I'll I'll shout out about curser to
the hackers out there like for us the
end goal is not to create some Majestic
code that is running very high
efficiency very optimized you know well
speak for yourself okay well most of the
most of the time when we're you know
coding our proof of con trying to make a
million bucks with my IOS app right hey
no I mean you're you're you're Devon I'm
talking about us as hackers right um you
know most of the time our our goal is to
just build PC this thing is very good
for getting a rough a rough solution to
a problem and uh and also adding some of
those nice to Hales that that make it a
lot more clear for example I'll just
share this little tip bit one of the
things that um is really negative about
um gdpr and and all these like cookie
stuff like you got to accept the cookies
is that everybody is just tune tuned
that out completely so it is extremely
easy to harvest a Click by just popping
up a little box saying like do you like
cookies you don't even need to say
anything else just say cookies they're
just like accept accept accept right so
it's extremely easy to harvest a click
in that in that scenario um and and so
uh you know in order to make your proof
of Concepts more reasonable more
beautiful more convincing to the team
which we've already talked about can you
know really increase your Bounty I think
up my experience has been up to 1.5
times your Bounty if you do a really
well good let me just throw a little
anecdote in here I woke up this morning
and checked my email inbox and um I had
a beautiful PC okay for the record like
I said I've been going deep on on some
applications we went through the effort
of writing an entire back-end server to
handle and proxy your class all this
stuff okay I get a notification this
morning treaser has up updated severity
from critical 9.0 To None no Joel please
okay report has transitioned to
depending program review dude you know
we do have a little bit of of like good
cop bad cop thing going on here with bug
Bounty cuz I feel like I'm relentlessly
optimistic about bug Bounty and I'm like
this is the great [__] about bug like I
love getting duped so I can see where I
where I messed up and I'm like I when I
get a dupe I want to quit
hacking oh my god dude I love it man
yeah no I mean I I and not to say it's
always the case but using cursor AI to
to tldr it for anybody who didn't follow
us through that monstrosity of a
conversation cursor is really good for
building p does that have nice nice to
haves especially in the web World um and
also just making quick modifications to
your code um so you don't have to go
look up all these things because us as
hackers we're not necessarily writing
the code every day we're reading the
code we're playing around with it um and
we can get it there it just takes more
time I think cursor is an excellent tool
for hackers because it takes away that
that um need to know all the syntax all
the flows and it does a lot of it if you
can describe the general concept right
for sure like it definitely and like it
doesn't have to be I think you know
unfortunately when when there's hype
clearly that video that I was talking
about like you know they want it to work
perfectly so that's why it was done in
the way that it that it does so they can
say you know write the back end for this
app using this file and it just just
works right quote unquote just works but
but like it just works because you did
all the the heavy lifting that being
said you can also get it to do that
stuff right and and it it can do a good
amount of work and pull in a lot of
context just out of the box like free
using Claude 3.5 like you know very very
you know it's very cool very very
interesting stuff I honestly the biggest
thing that I like struggle with is I pay
for chat
GPT Premium Plus or whatever um and I
have like access to 01 uh preview and
stuff I just want to hook it into that
and I don't want to pay for like a the
API stuff like a totally different
because it's like tokens and
stuff yeah do I mean do you think it's
better do you think like open I mean
here's the thing here's the thing
whether or not it's better I'm unsure
the fact that I'm paying for it is
really all it is so like I'm paying for
a version that should be better than
Claude 3.5 out of the box you know I I I
think that I think that the the Claude
products are probably better for code
stuff and I that's that's what I've
heard from people that know more about
AI than me um so that's what I've heard
as well but I've gone back and forth
with the two of them I I think the
biggest well to be fair I put it up on
very very difficult unfair challenges
where I'll be like generate a free to
script and it'll start to
hallucinate and I'm like ah man this
stuff is garbage and then I'll be like
generate a python script that like opens
a web server and do that perfectly and
obviously you know so I think it depends
on you know set your expectations
accordingly but it's still it's still
quite cool yeah okay so I I've got this
next item here on the doc Joel and I'm
I'm going to I'm going to talk through
it really quick but I'm also going to go
off on a little bit of a tangent okay
from a from a recent hacking experience
you never do that so and neither do I so
I'm just cautioning you you know so
you're not taken by surprise uh you know
give given our normal strict adherance
to the doc um right yeah okay so we we
got a write up here from um uh sinology
uh from summoning team uh he he was on
the Pod a couple months ago and it's a
great write up on uh whats up gold sqli
the thing that I wanted to highlight
from this and we'll link it down below
I'm not going to walk you through the
whole thing once again because like like
CNA does it's an amazing um detailed
write up of you know all the different
code blocks and and all the different
techniques and thought patterns that
that he went through so definitely a
recommended read I just want to pull a
couple things out of this okay so he
gets a a vanilla sqli and and I I I want
to say there's like this really badass
vanilla sqi just like first of all I
haven't found a SQL injection since 2015
but keep going I know right this is
crazy dude like people they they exist
they can find them there's been a couple
it's been literally almost 10 years
since I found a SQL
injection they're they're deep in there
how how are we not using prepared
statements folks come on dude and and
this is what he said I'm just going to
quote this thing he says uh and this
leads to a vanilla SQL injection as one
would expect from such a sophisticated
application
so one one burned two great bug so not
very good um real quick real quick real
quick I need to Pivot back to the cursor
stuff because this this this reminded me
of something that video I was talking
about I quote tweeted it when I first
saw it and I was like security Engineers
or what was it security researchers
rubbing their hands together the dev
develops an entire backend service
without knowing how it works this is
exactly how I feel dude like you know
it's like you got this awesome
sophisticated application secretly
behind the scenes cursor Claude 3.5
wrote this whole thing and it did it in
a way because it's like I want to do
this fast and quick and it's just going
to work and it accidentally created like
15 security vulnerabilities behind the
scenes but it works yeah no no no I I
think it's great job security for us as
long as there isn't a uh a you know
cursor equivalent of the security res we
need to land some AI sponsors here job
security I'm I'm seeing it now yeah
absolutely okay so now that you've gone
off on your little tangent we're going
back to the thing we got we got an sqli
here's what he does with this okay um he
what he ends up doing is a common SQL uh
I exploitation technique which is let me
overwrite the master password um for
this application right so I can just log
in as the admin and and get into the app
right um but in this specific
application this master password is
encrypted okay and so it's a it's not as
easy as just overwriting the password
and you can't register an account or
anything this is an unoth
bug so so what does he do um he Dives
deep into the encryption figures out
exactly how it it works and you can't
reproduce it you know it's Unique to a
random thing on the on that machine
right but what he does instead is he
finds an encryption Oracle okay and he
uses the SQL to read a an encrypted
piece of text from somewhere else in the
application that's in the data database
extract that out and set it as the
master password for the um for the
actual user and then proceeds to log in
right so I just want one thing I will
say is like
I this is one of those like you get to
this point and you're like okay how bad
do I want to destroy this application
because exactly uh I'm about to test
some things that are probably going to
break everything yes yeah no no and and
you know this is it's important to
notice uh note here that that
he's F he's targeting an application
that is offline right this is a this is
not a cloud instance this is a you know
okay okay this is him on his machine
with his thing you know don't go
overriding all this stuff with SQL
injections it's extremely dangerous and
I've been burned by it tons of people
have been burned by it so please don't
do that in production but um I think
that this was a really unique um cool
thing to do and I I I wanted to sort of
pivot off of the topic a little bit
because this whole concept of encryption
Oracle
um it's very interesting and it's very
applicable I think so um there's an app
that I've been testing a couple months
ago where there's a big piece of their
security was built off of this
encryption aspect that they had and um
and if you were able to get around that
encryption um you could really reliably
attack the application um and and so
this which I think is pretty common by
the way like um just like you know jwt's
for examp I I think like a great example
where like a JWT is one key leak or one
generation Oracle or one arbitrary Imp
in like Json injection like anything
like from being really catastrophic
right yeah absolutely and and and so I I
think a lot of hackers sort of shy away
from this cryptography piece because
it's very math heavy and it's very like
complex and you've got to understand a
lot of the the various pieces of the
system to be able to exploit it but um
it's extremely impactful and one of the
ones one of the attacks that I think is
really um consistently impactful if you
can figure it out is this Oracle thing
right if you can provide some some
string and that string will get
encrypted reliably and you can get that
encrypted value out there's a lot of
weird stuff you can do with that because
applications are not trusting or they're
they're not expecting that you can get
that encrypted value right and and so
they're they're trusting that and um and
so anytime you see something something
like that just like brainstorm a little
bit in your brain like how could I get
this how could I get this encrypted
value where could I where could I find
this and then actually what I did in the
specific environment was I set up a um a
kaido workflow that like you know maybe
15 minutes to write where um I would
inject at a specific spot I I'll keep it
too a little vague I'll I'll inject at a
specific spot and then note you know
where that uh I could tell in the
response whether or not my my data had
been encrypted and put in the response
or not um and and so I think that that
sort of thing uh is and then I navigated
the application naviga it didn't end up
paning out but uh I was proud of the
methodology because I think there are
very Niche cases where you can get that
that encryption Oracle and then apply it
to the app and it's really catastrophic
yeah so I've got I've got two tips on
that one is um if you think that you
have one uh try to pad in your data with
like something like a super super long
string like you know a thousand A's or
something and one common thing that
you'll see is you know the response
length goes up significantly when you
have that encryption Oracle like you
know the Valu is getting reflected in
there um the other thing is with with
the length side of it a lot of
applications aren't expecting large like
you know very large Json objects and
stuff and so oftentimes that will either
break at the web server level where it's
like trying to return a Content link
that is far far larger than it expected
or it will break at like you know the
library level where it might be trying
to craft the JWT or trying to craft um
you know that response token back that
it's generating for you that encryption
token um so yeah yeah large values is is
really useful that that length piece was
exactly one of one of the techniques I
used in in that application um and so
yeah there's definitely inflating the
size if you theorize that you might be
injecting into an encrypted context then
just inflate your input size and if the
output is also inflated then there's a
good chance that you're injecting
somewhere in that um and you might be
able you know depending on what's being
encrypted you know you could you could
do you know Json injection you could do
path reversals you could do you know lot
all sorts of stuff um yeah and this is
one of my favorite things to do you know
for like information gathering when I'm
looking at an application it's just like
fuzz the inputs with different types and
different things than what it's
expecting so if it's expecting a string
give it a list if it's or give it null
if it's like a Json like give it uh you
know the the the null type not not an
empty string um give it like extra
parameters give it inv valid Json just
Tred a bunch of different stuff because
eventually one of those is going to
raise an error and it's going to give
you something that's a bit revealing
about the application about how it's how
it's actually functioning yeah dude I um
when you said that it made me think of
something I don't know if you were
asleep or not because I know the time
zones didn't work super well for you but
there was a um there was a show in town
didn't see I didn't see it let's just
say there was a show and tell
given and let's just say fron was
wearing a ctvb
T-shirt and there was a shout out given
to ctvb podcast for something that has
been said in the history of the podcast
that may have had an application that's
all I'm gonna say that's all I'm gonna
say
for all right man let's uh let's move
along here so uh one of the things that
I I've been hacking on lately um there
was an ability for for me to do a file
upload um and in inside of this file
upload environment um there was
essentially a Rex for the the content
type that that of the file that you
could upload and it needed to start with
image slash and there was a um there was
a Rex for uh so that you couldn't do um
SVG plus XML right um so it's it's not
going to allow you to do uh xss via VIA
that and so I started researching some
of the the different cool like things
you can do with with content types if
you have a lot of flexibility over it
like there was in this scenario and I
settled upon this uh write up called
content-type d resarch by blackfan it's
a it's a GitHub repo on um on GitHub
it's it's a repo on GitHub and get re
GitHub yeah yeah yeah you know you're
welcome for that um and dude whenever
you see I see stuff like this I just get
happy you know like because we talked
about this before right like like
content type research like that is that
is that is so help f um because people
are going deep into these things that
are components of various attacks um and
and it contains a really nice table of
um content types that can be used for
xss and then response content types
tricks which was the thing that that
helped me in the scenario um so click
that link and scroll all the way down
I'm looking at it this is so weird dude
it's it's it blew my mind that this
content type is valid okay content-type
colon text/html
left parentheses
XXX that will that will trigger an xss
that will that will be parsed as text h
HTML even though there's no space it's
just a left parenthesis that is a a
valid delimiter in the content type
header do you find you have content type
injection pretty frequently um in file
uploads yes because what'll happen is is
you you'll upload a file right and
they'll be like WR wrapping an S3 policy
or whatever and then they'll upload the
thing to S3 and you can spe spe if the
content type that it should be served
with when you upload it to S3 um and so
I often find that they're doing some
sort of reject on the content type but
sometimes they just like statically say
all right we're GNA allow image JPEG
image PNG that sort of
thing so super cool yeah no this is this
is great I mean this is one of those
like meta you know you bookmark it and
like you know the next time you're you
realize that you have content type
injection yeah you're G be like oh [__]
where was that yeah content type
research repo yeah exactly and and and
then here's the cool thing about this
too you know if you can get it render
you don't have to necessarily control so
much of the of the body right you can
just control some arbitrary pieces of
the body um but if you can get the
content type to be something that will
be rendered as HTML then you you'll
still get xss um especially when you can
control the character set as well which
you can in a content type header um
because even if there's like some
restrictions on what type of characters
you can put in there you can play around
with the with the charet a little bit
and get the browser to interpret it as
as HTML um so really cool research here
the other one I wanted to shout out um
besides that weird delimiter of the of
the left parenthesis which I never would
have thought is um this first one right
here which is a multiple content type uh
header and one of the things I love
about this repo is there's just like a
link you can click to like prove it that
you don't have to like just take their
word for it like they've already
prepared a link and everything you can
just click and see if it pops in your
browser and it does man
so this is the content type header Tech
plane semicolon xals X comma text/html
right yeah my other favorite thing is
that they link for this one specifically
they link to the the whatwg org.org like
HTML spec that specifically says like
here's like yes you can put multiple
values in and here's like the different
formats and that you can you know you
can extract a mind type like you know
yeah it's it's super interesting it's
very nice so so so even if you have like
a strict Rex like must start with text
plane or something like that or or and
it's just not validating the chart set
or something like that um you can you
know put in a comma and then add another
content type header invalidate the first
one and then you're off to the races um
yeah so I think there's there's a lot of
um there's a lot of applications for
this sort of thing knowing the nuances
and sometimes it can even result in in
our CE if you are uploading to an actual
environment that will do serers side you
know rendering like for example if
you're able to get a uh a PHP file
uploaded or something like that so um
these tricks can result in in stored xss
absolutely very common but also um you
got to think about that bigger
application as well yeah yeah I mean
it's uh this is this is some awesome
research so I'm definitely going to be
starring this on GitHub and bookmarking
it nice um another another quick thing
we'll hit the kid stuff and then I'll
jump into another piece of really
awesome research um kaido released uh
version
0.41 um and this actually has a plugin
store which is awesome um so definitely
looking forward to seeing how this helps
some of the the distribution in kaido
plugins and I'm going to be uploading um
Expo uh one my kaido plugin and you know
maybe there's another kaido plugin in in
Dev right now with uh with another um
guest of the podcast so uh we we'll see
when that gets released because it's
kind of a monster it's it's gonna be a
big one to death but will say I will say
as like a kaido user like it's been very
difficult for me to sort of like follow
the yeah I mean like plugin stuff has
like shifted a lot right so like in the
beginning there was nothing right and
then there was even better which added
like a a way to sort of like you know
add stuff and then they they had like
the plugin library but Alo there there's
the um the workflow Library which I
think is also from even better or no
that one's from kaido right and then
like even better also has uh a way to
install bundle plugins or something and
now there's like a an
official something just like threw
something off your desk don't worry
about
that and now there's like an official
plugin store so I yeah I think it might
be good from the kaido side I know you
have uh you've got you've got a direct
line in there um but it might be good
for them to sort of like walk people
through like the right way to do this or
maybe a good way to migrate from all
those solutions to the recommended one
or something because it does I'm still a
little bit confused about like what
things I should be leaving installed and
you know what is even better providing
me versus the community plugin store
versus the workflows library versus you
know it's all a bit confusing it it is a
bit confusing you're right and that's
something that we're working on with
with with kaido that's something that
I've talked to the team about and I
think one of the ways we're going to
solve that soon hopefully uh is is get a
kaido GPT out there where you can ask it
questions like hey here's what I want to
do I want to you
know add this specific input and look
for this encrypted response in the
output right um and and then it'll say
okay you know if that's what you want to
do then you know XYZ this workflow is
your is your best bet or whatever right
um and and so it should be able to
provide suggestions for how you can
Implement various types of automation
you want to see in kaido um like you
said Joel I I'll go ahead and add a
disclaimer I am a uh I am a kaido
adviser I'm on the kaido team so um just
to shout that out there but I will
say we do and I just want to make this
as a a general announcement to the to
the ctbb listeners we do not talk about
things Andor advertise things on this
podcast that we do not endorse like like
that we haven't had experience with we
have turned down multiple five fig deals
to to advertise s because we don't like
the product um and so just just saying
if it's coming from us even if it's an
in an ad or if we're talking about it
like this is normally because we have
hands-on experience with it we we know
the person that's releasing it we know
they release quality work um so when I
talk about kaido I'm talking about kaido
because I literally use it every single
day um and so I I'll just put that out
there um yeah so I'm excited to see
where that where that goes there's
definitely
um improvements to be made but kaido is
moving very fast and they're getting a
lot of stuff right I think and um and
I'm excited to see uh I'm excited to
release this next plugin that I'm
working on man because I think it is
really going to change the game um for
kaido
Stuff um all right Joel we got we got
two writeups here um let me go ahead and
introduce this this NE this first one
so the way I stumbled let me just let me
just um Let me let me say this the way I
stumbled upon this write up is
orange and James two people that I James
Kettle two people that I have um note or
tweet notifications turned on for both
retweeted this write up right so if if
you see James and orange both retweet
something you need to go you need to go
read that right now yeah yeah right um
and so this is a write up by a a
researcher that I hadn't hadn't really
seen before rebane um and it is a super
cool client side chain
to get to exploit a to pretty
impactfully exploit a clickjacking in uh
Google Docs um did did you get a chance
to read through this one I know it's a
little bit lengthy no but I have it
already I have it bookmarked in my on my
Twitter I had it liked and bookmarked
already so before I put it on the do yes
yes so I remember i' had seen it and I
was like whoa that's that's pretty
interesting I I I like read like The you
know the little like synopsis and I was
like that feels like it should have
gotten probably more money but that that
was my first reac
well it it's really interesting and I
I'll present it for you as well then
it's it's a write up um on a that's a
clickjacking bug right so this is an
example it was paid I think like $5,000
from Google vrb so this is an example of
a clickjacking bug that has impact um
and the situation was uh this researcher
was able to craft a Google doc that
looked like it had a Google form in it
so pretty pretty standard embedding a
Google form in a doc um but when you
clicked the the button to submit the
Google form it would give you
access to or give the attacker access to
the victims uh go all of their Google
Drive um which was very impactful um and
no big deal so yeah right and um so
there there's a lot of really useful
Gadgets in this write up so that's why I
wanted to cover it because like it's
great to see a a really cool client side
chain there's like three redirect chain
together and um those redirects are not
fixed by the way um so it's very helpful
from a gadget perspective I um but it's
also really really helpful to understand
um like some of these features about
Google drive as well um I did not know
that Google Drive had a root directory
it's just called root and everybody's
Google Drive has this and and you can
grab it from like looking at your your
network request they explain how to do
it in the writeup but you you can grab
the ID for that folder and if you share
that folder anything you put in Google
Drive is now shared with that other
person yeah super interesting that the
Google Drive like sharing permission
stuff because um I mean I know we've
dealt with this a little bit from the
ctbb side actually but um but yeah like
folder sharing permissions are um they
like carry through right so like you
said like anything that gets added to a
folder yeah gets shared and anything in
and anything below that folder even like
subfolders inherit the per the
permissions from the parent yeah so it's
like super easy to kind of shoot
yourself in the foot by accident by you
know you set like a parent folder to so
everybody can access it and and then
suddenly everybody can access everything
yeah yeah absolutely so so here are some
of the gadgets that I wanted to shout
out from this okay you got that root
folder thing which is very interesting
and then you've also got a super useful
Gadget um from YouTube and this is a a
redirect chain that will allow you to um
go from
www.youtube.com which is often used for
embedding YouTube videos um in the right
up they do a path traversal um on
embedding YouTube videos so this I could
see this being very useful and other
environments as well um and you you land
on um you can land on a Google doc site
but you can also land on www.google.com
which we all know if we've listened to
the podcast has an open redirect via the
slamp endpoint to get you out so I've
got a I've got a uh a URL that I'll put
in the notes for this um episode that
starts with ww.youtube.com and will'll
end on my attacker control domain um and
I can see this being extremely helpful
for for client side chains very similar
to the one in this in report um and also
for anything that is trying to parse a
YouTube video you might even be able if
it's following redirects you might even
be able to get an ssrf out of this um so
definitely definitely some impact impact
there um just I realized we got a little
distracted the actual um the the expit
that this person comes up with in the
end is you know they they're sharing the
whole I I did say that okay that's good
the the whole Google Drive um and and so
there's lots of really cool tips
adjacent to that um in this write up as
well um and then let let me go ahead and
grab one more thing out of here that I
had
um okay yeah I remembered what it is
dude did you see did you see at the end
of this write up I'm just going to read
a quote from this everything on this
page is just HTML and CSS crafted with
love no images no JavaScript or other
resources and it's all gzipped into 31
kiloby so this whole right up click on
the link dude there's like it looks like
there's a bu of um images from like
Google Drive in here none of these are
images this is all wait this this
lunatic of a person wrote all of this in
HTML and CSS only no JavaScript even bro
what the so like there there are
pictures throughout this whole write up
and if you click on them you can like
select all the text these are like I can
undo and redo the checkbox and type in
right it's crazy right what what is this
it's nuts it's that's crazy it's very
very cool so um kind of a shout out to
them like l. horse um is a really cool
blog and I went to go read a little bit
more about this and they have another um
article called stealing your telegram
account in 10 seconds flat and I was
like okay what's going on here and
essentially it outlines an exploit that
they weren't able to fully develop but
essentially when you send a message in
telegram that contains a specific domain
in it it will attach the C like the the
the the person's credentials who is
receiving that that domain to the link
so you click on it and you're
automatically aued into the domain um
for telegram related like short links
and stuff like that um so one if you're
a telegram hacker because I know they
have a bug Bounty program uh sus that
very thoroughly because that is super
sketchy and um and also it they outlined
a very cool attack factor which is like
if you send a message to somebody and
you have their phone you can get
persistent access on their phone by
clicking that link and then just
changing the URL up at the top of the
browser very quickly to a URL that you
control and it contains their off token
in it and you're just very easily able
to hijack their account in like sub 10
seconds um so I think that was I thought
that was a really cool write up I don't
think they got a bounty for it I don't
know that they even submitted it but I
think that kind of attack Vector is I
think that kind of functionality is not
something you really want to have in
your applications so um you know whether
it be a low or a medium I would have I
would have still reported that I think
yeah I mean that's that's super crazy
that's uh that's a really interesting
Insight that I I didn't actually realize
yeah especially especially when it's an
application like telegram which claims
to be like super super secure and
security oriented right um to have
something like that I think is really
not a great idea definitely gonna get
yourself pwned somehow with that yeah
yeah exactly um all right man Joel
that's all I had on the doc for today
you got anything anything else before we
wrap it up or is that the Pod yeah I
think that's I think that's the PO I got
a lot of Juicy notes I got to make sure
I'm getting all my plugins from the
plugin store yeah I gotta look at some
content type injection so hell yeah man
this is this is good stuff good episode
dude all right that's the Pod peace bu
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there